<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>BLØGGN</title><description>BLØGGN</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.7</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 21:13:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>(Untitled)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;It's been a long time since I published anything other than a portfolio on the web, but that ends today. I've built this blog with Ghost and Buster and it's hosted in Github Pages under a domain name I own. This is great for me because I don't have to&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/2015/11/15/untitled-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">055e4017-d0bf-4cb9-99e1-37dab4e97c23</guid><category>code</category><dc:creator>Ian</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 21:11:19 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It's been a long time since I published anything other than a portfolio on the web, but that ends today. I've built this blog with Ghost and Buster and it's hosted in Github Pages under a domain name I own. This is great for me because I don't have to worry about exposing an admin interface to the web, everything is static so it loads quickly, and making new posts is still easy because I can fire up Ghost on my machine, write a new post, then compile and publish it to Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran into a few pitfalls while working on the setup so I thought I'd mention them here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create your Github Pages repo first, and do it on the Github site! All you need to do is create a new repo called &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.github.io&lt;/code&gt;. Mine's &lt;code&gt;ihgrant.github.io&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you have created the repo, install ghost on your machine locally. You'll end up with a directory full of folders like &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;core&lt;/code&gt;, and so on. Clone your github pages repo next to these, into a directory called &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;, like so: &lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.github.io.git static&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installing buster can be confusing if you're not familiar with Python or its package manager (like me). Fortunately, although OS X does come with a recent version of Python installed, it does not have &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt;, Python's package manager installed, even though if you installed Python yourself, pip would come with it. You can, however, get pip with Homebrew - and that's what I did.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;at this point, when you run &lt;code&gt;buster generate&lt;/code&gt; from your current directory (the one you installed ghost into) it'll populate that new &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; folder with the files for your static blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once that's done, all you need to do is run &lt;code&gt;buster deploy&lt;/code&gt; to commit those files to the repo and push it up to Github!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to Akshit Khurana (&lt;a href="https://github.com/axitkhurana/buster"&gt;https://github.com/axitkhurana/buster&lt;/a&gt;) for Buster, and Stefan Scherer (&lt;a href="https://stefanscherer.github.io/setup-ghost-for-github-pages/"&gt;https://stefanscherer.github.io/setup-ghost-for-github-pages/&lt;/a&gt;) for giving me extra info to figure out what I was doing wrong. There are a fair number of pieces to slot together!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>